Guide to the Duke University Marching Band (DUMB) records, 1958-1978 and undated UA.31.07.0006
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University Marching Band (DUMB) records
1958-1978 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Marching Band
UA.31.07.0006
1.5 Linear Feet
In existence since the early 1900s, the Duke University Marching Band (DUMB) is an integral part of Duke University sports, providing music and vocal support to university games such as football and basketball. Materials in the collection include administrative records (of the DUMB organization), correspondence, handbooks, game schedules, flyers, the DUMB newsletter, drum heads from the 1958 Orange Bowl and 1961 Cotton Bowl football games, and rosters of alumni.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Duke University Marching Band (DUMB) records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1973, 1976, and 2017.
Historical Note
In existence since the early 1900's, the Duke University Marching Band (DUMB) is an integral part of Duke University sports, providing music and vocal support to university games such as football and basketball. Playing home games, close out-of-town games and any Bowl games, DUMB has established a reputation for performing creative and highly entertaining halftime shows.
Collection Overview
Materials in the collection include administrative records (of the organization), correspondence, handbooks, game schedules, flyers, the DUMB newsletter, a signed drum head from the 1958 Orange Bowl football games, a drum head from the 1961 Cotton Bowl football game, and rosters of alumni.
Collection Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Related Material
Paul Bryan Papers, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Artifacts and Relics Collection, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
University Archives Photograph Collection, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Marching Bands -- United State -- North Carolina -- Durham; Marching Bands; Duke University. Marching Band
- Administrative Records, 1969-1973 and undated (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1961-1974 and undated (Box 1)
- Duke University Marching Band in the News, 1958-1978 and undated (Box 1)
- DUMBooks, 1961, 1966, 1969, 1971, 1972, 1978 (Box 1)
- DUMBugle, 1972-1975 (Box 1)
- DUMB Hymnals, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
- Flyers, 1971 and undated (Box 1)
- Game Schedules and Information, 1970-1973 and undated (Box 1)
- Marching Band Members from 1914-1975 (Box 1)
- Orange Bowl drum head, 1958 (Box 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Drum head used in the 1958 Orange Bowl game in Miami, FL, between Duke University and the University of Oklahoma. The drum head was ruptured during practice and signed by members of the drum corps.
- Cotton Bowl drum head, 1961 (Box 3)